<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Benhur</title><link>https://benhur.me/</link><description>Recent content on Benhur</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 17:23:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://benhur.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About</title><link>https://benhur.me/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://benhur.me/about/</guid><description>I’m a product designer currently working at frog, the design agency with a background in architecture and experience design. I make tech and digital products useful and delightful to use as I employ human psychology to craft interactions.
Other than that, I’m a keen learner, I’m interested in football, f1, archery, reading and astronomy. I love to dabble in code and writing.</description></item><item><title>WhatsApp showed you what they stand for. What can you do?</title><link>https://benhur.me/posts/whatsapp-and-privacy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 17:23:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://benhur.me/posts/whatsapp-and-privacy/</guid><description>Alternatives to Whatsapp that provide a good experience. Why? ![Signal app icon in a blue background](https://benhur.me/img/WhatsApp-privacy /Signal.jpeg)
Surprisingly, this time, people from all over the world have been seeking for alternative platforms to WhatsApp that has dominated the cross-platform messenger market for 11-years. Let us discuss what are the reasons to switch and why Signal is the best platform to switch to in terms of Privacy, User Control, User Experience and feature sets for the major target audience.</description></item><item><title>What can astronomy teach us about humility?</title><link>https://benhur.me/posts/astronomy-humility/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 16:33:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://benhur.me/posts/astronomy-humility/</guid><description>300,000 years ago when the first homo sapien set foot on the plains of Africa, little did it know that someday, it would bring the whole of planet Earth under its clutches. It did not know it would mass murder billions of animals for meat, it did not know it had the power to alter the climate and cause widespread destruction on a global scale.
We, humans have evolved to become the dominant species of a planet in a small period when compared to the cosmic timeline.</description></item><item><title>Explorative Play</title><link>https://benhur.me/posts/explorative-play/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 20:45:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://benhur.me/posts/explorative-play/</guid><description>The future of Explorative Play and what this means for designers &amp;ldquo;Consciousness narrows as we get older”— Michael Pollan What is explorative play? Explorative play gives a sandbox experience for kids to simulate adult life. In her book, how emotions are made, Lisa Barett, the psychologist says that 90% of our brain is running on internal simulation and the rest 10% of input from external world. The external stimulus is what the brain uses to test these internal simulations.</description></item></channel></rss>