<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Benhur</title><link>https://benhur.me/</link><description>Recent content on Benhur</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 15:31:56 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://benhur.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About</title><link>https://benhur.me/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://benhur.me/about/</guid><description>I’m a product designer currently working at frog, the design agency with a background in architecture and experience design. I make tech and digital products useful and delightful to use as I employ human psychology to craft interactions.
Other than that, I’m a keen learner, I’m interested in football, f1, archery, reading and astronomy. I love to dabble in code and writing.</description></item><item><title>What Could Meta Bring to the Metaverse Table?</title><link>https://benhur.me/posts/meta/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 15:31:56 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://benhur.me/posts/meta/</guid><description>Meta is quickly becoming a new name and is becoming synonymous with the infamous metaverse we all seem to be raving about. It remains to be seen how meta, the former facebook brand is updated with new business models surrounding the metaverse and if it would follow the best ethical and privacy friendly practices it has failed to do so far.
Centralised vs Decentralised metaverses Meta prides itself on building the next generation immersive 3D experiences with avatars for work and leisure.</description></item><item><title>Designing for the next generation mental models</title><link>https://benhur.me/posts/next-generation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 20:27:24 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://benhur.me/posts/next-generation/</guid><description>Designing for the next generation. Think about a time when you taught your parents how to use a smartphone or any digital interface. You probably spent a good chunk of time trying to explain how to get from one screen to the next by tapping on weird blocks that claim they stand for something. Yes, I’m looking at you, the dot button which has additional options within it that makes no sense but it does now because someone decided so.</description></item><item><title>How can Zero Knowledge Proof be used by Designers to Design for Privacy</title><link>https://benhur.me/posts/zkproof/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 15:59:28 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://benhur.me/posts/zkproof/</guid><description>Zero-knowledge Proofs Zero knowledge proofs have been used to make the information that is exchanged on the blockchain anonymous and private. Zero knowledge proofs are mathematical proofing system where the prover (the party who has to prove something) to the verifier (The other party who would verify the statement) without conveying additional information.
The statement being conveyed has to only consist of the fact that the prover knows or possesses the secret rather than telling the whole secret to the verifier or any other third party.</description></item><item><title>How I Created a Digital Second Brain to Optimise Learning</title><link>https://benhur.me/posts/knowledge-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 21:15:15 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://benhur.me/posts/knowledge-management/</guid><description>Many of us spend a long time on the internet these days, consuming and learning new things only to forget them because there’s always more new and exciting things to learn about.
In addition to that, we also consume information through various mediums like twitter, podcasts, books, articles and newsletters. It can be hard to keep up with them periodically and when you need that particular piece of information you read a year ago, it can be hard to find it.</description></item><item><title>Why the concept of immersive virtual worlds and metaverses could fail</title><link>https://benhur.me/posts/human-limitations/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 00:09:22 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://benhur.me/posts/human-limitations/</guid><description>Recreating figments of reality has been in our DNA The oldest cave paintings that have been discovered so far, dates back to almost 45,000 years ago. We, homosapiens have always been intrigued about the world around us and tried to recreate it in different forms throughout history. Instead of being functional, these paintings tell us that people loved to imitate or even redefine reality.
The earliest forms of writing were found around 5000 years ago in the form of Quipu.</description></item><item><title>How can web3 change the game for designers</title><link>https://benhur.me/posts/web3-and-modern-services/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 11:34:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://benhur.me/posts/web3-and-modern-services/</guid><description>For the sake of this article, let’s keep web 3 explanation super simple. Web 3.0’s decentralised protocol will enable people on the internet to own and be compensated for their time and data of all forms, whereas today, all of these data are being exploited by centralised giants.
We might have seen different posts talk about how this could change our society. While these new dimension of products have hard to understand mechanics and you could lose money due to the poor design language of these platforms.</description></item><item><title>How I use Bear, Things and Apple shortcuts to supercharge productivity</title><link>https://benhur.me/posts/bear-and-things-app/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 12:35:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://benhur.me/posts/bear-and-things-app/</guid><description>What is bear? Bear is a productivity / notes app Bear is an incredibly powerful text-editor that is made by a small team from Germany. The attention to detail, privacy and encryption, the relative speed is what drove me to use bear. I’ve been using notion for two years now and one fine day, they decided to lock me out of my account when I lost access to my email (I had an email and password setup to login) Notion does not have a way to recover your account if you lose access to the email.</description></item><item><title>Explorative Play</title><link>https://benhur.me/posts/explorative-play/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 20:45:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://benhur.me/posts/explorative-play/</guid><description>The future of Explorative Play and what this means for designers &amp;ldquo;Consciousness narrows as we get older”— Michael Pollan What is explorative play? Explorative play gives a sandbox experience for kids to simulate adult life. In her book, how emotions are made, Lisa Barett, the psychologist says that 90% of our brain is running on internal simulation and the rest 10% of input from external world. The external stimulus is what the brain uses to test these internal simulations.</description></item><item><title>WhatsApp showed you what they stand for. What can you do?</title><link>https://benhur.me/posts/whatsapp-and-privacy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 17:23:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://benhur.me/posts/whatsapp-and-privacy/</guid><description>Alternatives to Whatsapp that provide a good experience. Why? Surprisingly, this time, people from all over the world have been seeking for alternative platforms to WhatsApp that has dominated the cross-platform messenger market for 11-years. Let us discuss what are the reasons to switch and why Signal is the best platform to switch to in terms of Privacy, User Control, User Experience and feature sets for the major target audience.</description></item><item><title>What can astronomy teach us about humility?</title><link>https://benhur.me/posts/astronomy-humility/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 16:33:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://benhur.me/posts/astronomy-humility/</guid><description>300,000 years ago when the first homo sapien set foot on the plains of Africa, little did it know that someday, it would bring the whole of planet Earth under its clutches. It did not know it would mass murder billions of animals for meat, it did not know it had the power to alter the climate and cause widespread destruction on a global scale.
We, humans have evolved to become the dominant species of a planet in a small period when compared to the cosmic timeline.</description></item></channel></rss>